Miguel Gonzalez

Senior Fullstack Software Developer, Engineering Manager, CSPO

Professional Profile

A dedicated technologist with over 20 years of professional software development experience. I have designed, developed and maintained web, mobile, desktop and telephone-based software applications; provided third tier customer and system support; provisioned on-premises and cloud-based infrastructure; managed and recruited teams of software developers; and served as a product owner on several agile projects.

Work Experience

Senior Software Developer, Backend

Recharge Payments | Remote | 2021-2022

Responsible for provisioning, maintaining and developing Google Cloud Function microservices that process millions of messages an hour using HTTP and PubSub triggered events.

- Maintained and became subject matter expert on microservices that synced discounts between Recharge and Shopify.
- Developed pattern to secure HTTP driven GCP Cloud Functions.
- Developed email notification microservices capable of sending event driven templated emails.
- Configured Open Telemetry Collector to receive SignalFX formatted metrics and export them to the SignalFX ingress.
- Contributed to Open Telemetry Collector open source ecosystem.
- Interviewed and mentored interns during the summer of 2022.
- Led project to request shipping rates using Shopify's subscription contract GraphQL API's.

Senior Software Developer

Tresta, Inc | Tallahassee, FL | 2014 - 2021

Senior Full Stack Software Developer on the PATLive product team.

- Migrated on-premises based ACD platform to cloud and provisioned SIP trunking to enable a 200 agent contact center to go remote and grow to 1600 agents during the Covid-19 pandemic.
- Assisted with migration of on-premises VMWare servers to VMWare cloud on AWS.
- Developed Kubernetes based telephony platform prototype.
- Developed OpenSIPS and FreeSWITCH based VOIP platform integrating with Genesys Cloud to deliver interactions to agents.
- Developed customer facing web and mobile applications allowing users to view leads, analytics, voice and call recordings.
- Developed agent facing web application which prompts agents to answer interactions, take leads for customers and control calls.
- Developed web socket enabled SMS messaging web client.
- Developed Windows and Linux application deployment scripts.

Manager, Software Development

PATLive | Tallahassee, FL | 2011 - 2014

As manager of our Software Development department, I oversaw resource management, evaluation, and technical recruiting. Our department grew from a team of six to three teams each with 10 developers. I continued to perform software development and support duties during this period of growth.

- Developed Call Tracking Application. Features included toll-free and local telephone numbers, call recording, call analytics, dynamic number replacement and click2call.
- · Managed FDOT Sunpass IVR project.
- Developed a cloud-based contact center for DCF with on-premises and remote agents throughout the state of Florida.
- Received Scrum Alliance Product Owner certification.

Contact

St. Augustine, Florida

(850) 294-1069

miguelg@gmail.com

miguelgonzalez.dev

inkedin.com/in/dev-miguel

github.com/hex1848

Education

MIS

1999-2002

Florida State University

Skills

HTML

JavaScript

CSS

C#

.NET Framework / Core

SQL

NoSQL

Bash

Powershell

Python

PlantUML

VOIP

FreeSWITCH

OpenSIPS

Linux

Windows

Docker

Kubernetes

Terraform

OpenTelemetry

AWS

GCP

Agile / SCRUM

Software Developer

PATLive | Tallahassee, FL | 1999 - 2011

Hired as a part-time web developer while taking undergraduate course work, I was tasked with developing a web based unified messaging platform to help customers manage an existing telephone-based communications service. Upon graduation in 2002, I was promoted to full-time Software Developer and promoted to a Senior Software Developer role in 2005.

- Developed Unified Messaging web application.
- Developed FEMA Map Assistance contact center application in partnership with IBM.
- Maintained company CRM, ticketing and contact center applications.